When you come into one pose that stretches particular muscles, it's always good to come into a counter pose to stretch the opposing muscles.
So I'm going to have Gina extend her feet out.
She's going to demonstrate this for you with Upavistha Konasana to an extreme ease pose or a reverse plank pose.
She's seated in dandasana right now with her feet flexed towards her nose, sitting up nice and tall.
She's going to inhale and reach her arms up to the sky.
And then she's going to exhale forward into Parsvottonasana or a forward bend.
Good.
So the counter pose to this, Gina is going to lengthen up, take her hands back, press into the hands and open up her chest, roll her shoulders back.
Then she's going to press through her big toe mounds, press big toes into the ground as she lifts her hips up.
If it's okay for your neck, you can let the neck just drop back if not you want to keep it right in line with your spine.
Good.
Now I'm just going to gently press into Gina's toes right here so that she gets that stretch through the top of her feet and then taking my feet on either side, I'm going to use my hands to lift her up and just help her come into that stretch just a little more deeply.
And then we're just going to ask Gina to come right back on down again.
Good.